## **Executive leader driving business transformation.**

Luis possesses a unique background that combines strategic management consulting, digital marketing and entrepreneurship with strong commercial acumen. With over 20 years of experience in leadership roles across multiple industries and geographies, Luis is a proven expert in conceiving and implementing forward-thinking business solutions for global companies while inspiring and cultivating multidisciplinary teams.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### PRESIDENT AND CEO

Feb 2019 - Dec 2020

**Lonely Planet** - Nashville, TN

- Hired by owner to fix the company and sell it.
- Revamped digital strategy and created new revenue models.
- Successfully exited the business, sold to Red Ventures in 2020.

#### PARTNER AND MANAGING DIRECTOR

Feb 2014 - Feb 2019

The Boston Consulting Group - Manhattan Beach, CA

First homegrown partner of the BCG Digital Ventures, with individual sales of over \$10M in the first three years.

- Led the ecommerce and last-mile logistics strategy for Walmart and Sam's Club in Mexico.
- Conceived the first P2P payments platform MACH for BCI in Chile.
- Revamped the mobile experience for Citibanamex in Mexico.
- Reimagined the credit card customer journey for the National Australia Bank.
- Identified adjacent new business opportunities for a BNZ in New Zealand.

#### **COFOUNDER - CHIEF CLIENT OFFICER & HEAD OF USER EXPERIENCE**

Oct 2009 - Feb 2014

**Leapfactor** – Mexico City, Mexico; Miami, FL

Privately funded startup with 60+ employees in the enterprise mobility space.

- Started as the CMO defining company strategy, positioning and messaging and leading the product portfolio.
- Emerged as the Chief Client Officer and individually served and deployed apps across 50+ clients.
- Lead the UX and creative teams to foster client satisfaction, user adoption and delineate product strategy.
- Oversaw operations of the product development, support, analytics and client services organizations.
- Notable Clients: AstraZeneca, Avon, Bayer, HD Supply, JP Morgan Chase, L'Oréal, SAP.

#### **COUNTRY MANAGER**

Feb 2009 - Oct 2009

**<u>Latin3</u>** - Mexico City, Mexico

Award-winning digital agency founded in 2000 and focused on the Latin American and US Hispanic markets.

- Head of the Mexico office overseeing the day-to-day operations of the agency.
- Turned around agency increasing revenue 400% with new accounts and selling new services to existing clients.
- Negotiated contracts and redefined value-driven relationships to ensure continuous revenue streams.
- Created new and advanced marketing practices that were new to the marketplace (i.e. mobile and social media).
- Notable Clients: Banamex (Citigroup), Cablevision, Nextel.

# **DIRECTOR, NMS LATINO**

May 2008 - Feb 2009

New Media Strategies - Washington DC

Meredith's (NYSE: MDP) social media firm whose influence changed the jargon of Web 2.0, according to Wired.

- Recruited as the architect of a new business unit offering social media strategies aimed to the Hispanic Markets.
- Developed go-to-market strategy, detailed market analysis, growth and staffing plans.
- Steered new sales pitches and increased contract value by at least 25% in every existing account penetrated.
- Provided thought leadership by writing blogs and actively speaking at industry events.
- Notable Clients: Nokia, Pepsi, Volkswagen, Warner Brothers.

May 2005 - May 2008

### MANAGING DIRECTOR, BRAVO UNO-A-UNO

The Bravo Group - New York City, NY

A WPP (NYSE:WPP) subsidiary established in 1975 as Young and Rubicam's leading US Hispanic Agency.

- Leader of new business unit with P&L responsibility offering direct, experiential and digital marketing services.
- Meshed the strengths and skills of a traditional advertising agency with digital practices and digital thinking.
- Increased profitability by outsourcing and building strategic alliances with other agencies in the WPP network.
- Deep involvement in new business development while effectively balancing the day-to-day operations.
- Notable Clients: <u>Chevron</u>, <u>HP</u>, <u>Mazda</u>, <u>Jaguar</u>, <u>Land Rover</u>, <u>Microsoft</u>, <u>Sears</u>, <u>The New York Times</u>, <u>Wrigley</u>, <u>Wyeth</u>.

#### **BUSINESS SOLUTIONS MANAGER / PRODUCT MANAGER**

Nov 2001 - Apr 2005

Neoris - Mexico City, Mexico; Rosario, Argentina; Miami, FL

A CEMEX (NYSE: CX) company and one of largest IT consulting and systems integration company Latin America.

- Designed strategies and programs to deliver operational efficiencies and elevate marketing results.
- Responsible for product specifications, roadmaps and business strategy definition for new company's offering.
- Project leader for over 50 intranet and website development projects in multiple geographies.
- Senior Consultant specialized in digital marketing, knowledge management and emerging technologies.
- Notable Clients: <u>CEMEX</u>, <u>CFE</u>, <u>DESC</u>, <u>Ford Motor Company</u>, <u>SCA</u>, <u>New York Life</u>.

#### WEB DESIGN MANAGER

Nov 1999 - Nov 2001

Alterbrain (acquired by Neoris in 2001) - Mexico City, Mexico

A conglomerate of companies that became one of the largest e-builders in Mexico, Brazil, Argentina and the US.

- Managed day-to-day operations, project planning, staffing and processes in the "Front End" group.
- Leader of the award-winning creative department and information architecture team.
- Engaged and grew client relationships by becoming the main point of contact.
- Led an effort to synchronize creative and web design methodologies with Rational Unified Process.
- Notable Clients: <u>Coca-Cola</u>, <u>Kimberly-Clark</u>, <u>Mexicana Airlines</u>, <u>Motorola</u>, <u>Unilever</u>, <u>Zurich</u>.

# WEB PRODUCER

Aug 1999 - Nov 1999

**Activamente** - Mexico City, Mexico

A leading Latin-American Marketing & Innovation group, also known for being the first digital agency in Mexico.

- Worked closely with clients to develop & implement innovative Internet advertising strategies.
- Hands-on every aspect, from content development and art direction to project and account management.
- Analyzed client data to identify key trends and insights and performed extensive competitive research.
- Lead creative of a critically important and highly visible consumer-facing website citrus.com.mx.
- Notable Clients: <u>Domecq</u>, <u>Bristol-Myers Squibb</u>.

## **EDUCATION, HONORS, AWARDS & SPEAKING ENGAGEMENTS**

# BA IN COMMUNICATIONS (Licenciatura Ciencias de la Comunicación)

1995 - 1999

• <u>Universidad Intercontinental (UIC)</u> - Mexico City, Mexico

# DIPLOMA FOR INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY (Diplomado: Tecnologías de la Información)

1998

- <u>Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM)</u> Mexico City, Mexico
- Multiple International Speaker engagements

2007 to date

• Board of Advisors for Grupo Reforma on reforma.com

2001 - 2002 and 2010

• Coauthor of eBook: El Modelo de la Nueva Agencia (www.lanuevagencia.com.ar)

2009

• Gold winner in the AdAge Creative awards and Diente de Oro for consultoriodelpuma.com

2008